Guide to the Bernard Gotfryd Photograph Collection PR 276
New-York Historical Society
Bernard Gotfryd photograph collection
1960-2011 (bulk 1961-1990)
New-York Historical Society
PR 276
10.78 Linear feet (16 boxes plus four flat file folders)
The Bernard Gotfryd Photograph Collection spans the period from 1960-2011 and primarily contains portraits of prominent people, photographs of New York City, material related to Gotfryd's career as a photographer, and materials related to his activities as a Holocaust Survivor speaker and author.
Provenance
Gift of Bernard Gotfryd, 2008. Additional items received in 2009, 2010, and 2011.
Access Restrictions
The collection is open to qualified researchers. Portions of the collection that have been photocopied or microfilmed will be brought to the researcher in that format; microfilm can be made available through Interlibrary Loan.
Arrangement
The collection is divided by format and subject into five series: Slides, Photographs, Oversize Material, Manuscript Material, and Holocaust Survivor Material. The series are further divided by topic, with Portraits and Subjects arranged separately. Portraits are arranged alphabetically by the sitter's name. Subjects are arranged alphabetically by topic. In some cases where multiple prints exist of a subject a separate folder is assigned.
The cross-reference "See:" indicates that the item is filed elsewhere under the listed name. "See also:" indicates where additional related materials are filed for that subject.
Scope and Contents
The Bernard Gotfryd Photograph Collection contains over 1000 photographs and several folders of manuscript material spanning the period from 1961-2011. The collection primarily contains portraits of prominent people, photographs of New York City, material related to Gotfryd's career as a photographer, and materials related to his activities as a Holocaust Survivor speaker and author. The bulk of the photographs and career-related manuscript material range from 1963-1988, while the bulk of the Holocaust Survivor material ranges from 1990-2009. The collection is divided into five series: Slides, Photographs, Oversize Material, Manuscript Material, and Holocaust Survivor Material
Series I. Slides is comprised of mainly 35mm, mounted slides as well as several 120mm slides taken from 1963 to 1991. Images include portraits, locations and events and are divided into three subseries: Portraits; Subjects; Subjects-New York City. See the container list for the names of portrait subjects and the topics of events.
Series II. Photographs is primarily comprised of gelatin silver prints and a few color photographs between 8 x 10 and 16 x 20, taken between 1962 and 1987. It is divided into five subseries comprising unmounted and mounted photographs of prominent individuals and of events and locations. Subject names or topics are listed in the container list.
Series III. Oversize Material contains mounted and unmounted photographic prints larger than 16 x 20 as well as various oversize clippings and ephemera.
Series IV. Manuscript Material contains material related to Gotfryd's career as a photojournalist and his work as an author and lecturer. The material is divided into two subseries: Correspondence and Ephemera.
Series V. Holocaust Survivor Material, dating between 1990 and 2011, contains materials relating to Bernard Gotfryd's speaking engagements and writings about the Holocaust. The series includes copies of three of Gotfryd's books, general correspondence, thank you notes and artwork from students and adults, writing drafts, and magazines with his articles or stories.
Biographical Note
Bernard Gotfryd was born in 1924 in Radom, Poland, and became interested in photography at an early age. When World War II broke out and schools were closed to Jewish students, Gotfryd found work as an apprentice in a photography studio. While working in the studio, he began aiding the Polish underground by passing on photographs taken by Nazi officers of war atrocities. After an unsuccessful escape attempt in October 1943, Gotfryd was apprehended and shipped to Maidanek. By the war's end, Gotfryd had survived six concentration camps.
In 1947, Gotfryd immigrated to the United States, where he worked as a photographer and studied photojournalism. After being drafted into the U.S. Army in 1949 and going through basic training, Gotfryd was assigned to the Signal Corps as a combat photographer. In 1952, he married his wife, Gina. They lived in Astoria, Queens until early 1954, when they moved to the Cambria Heights section of Queens. They raised two children, Howard and Eva, in this neighborhood, before relocating in the early 1970's to Forest Hills, Queens.
Gotfryd joined the staff of Newsweek in 1957, where he worked for more than thirty years. His photography for Newsweek encompasses a broad sampling of celebrity portraits and events in the U.S. in the 1960's, 1970's and 1980's, including numerous photos in and around New York City.
It was while working for Newsweek, covering the Holocaust Survivors Gathering in Washington, D.C., in April 1983 that Gotfryd was moved to write about his own experiences. First published in Newsweek, his stories were published in 1990 as a collection, titled Anton the Dove Fancier and Other Tales of the Holocaust. An expanded edition of the book was published in 2000. In addition the book Widuje ich w snach: Nowe Opowiadania (I can see them in my dreams: The new stories) was published in English and Polish in 2008, and Stolarz Isaak, Em Murem in polish in 2009. Gotfryd also has given numerous talks to school children and others about his experiences during World War II.
Sources: Gotfryd, Bernard. Anton the Dove Fancier and Other Tales of the Holocaust. New York: Washington Square Press, Pocket Books, 1990.
Gotfryd, Bernard. Anton the Dove Fancier and Other Tales of the Holocaust (expanded edition). Cleveland: John Hopkins University Press, 2000.
Gotfryd, Bernard. The Intimate Eye: Portraits by Bernard Gotfryd. New York: Riverside Book Company, [2006].
Related Materials
Four other organizations hold collections of Bernard Gotfryd's photographs and papers:
The Library of Congress: http://www.loc.gov/pictures/item/2010650142/
The Hoover Institution: http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt8q2nf3rc/?query=Gotfryd
The Brooklyn Historical Society: http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/bhs/v1987_003_gotfryd/
The Hebrew Home at Riverdale: http://www.hebrewhome.org/exh_gotfryd.asp
- Series I. Slides
  Arrangement
  Slides are arranged by subject. Portraits are alphabetical by sitter's name and dates are listed when given.
  Scope and Contents
  Subseries I.1 Portraits dates from approximately 1963 to 1991. Portraits of artists, athletes, authors, musicians, politicians, and other well-known figures make up the bulk of this group. These images include both formal portraits and candid shots. Slides are arranged alphabetically by name with cross-references when more than one person appears in a single image.
  Subseries I.2 Subjects includes images of locations and events outside New York City, as well as general subjects such as "Military", "Science & Medicine" and "Technology & Industry". "Pop Culture" includes photographs of television screens, showing coverage of newsworthy events such as the 1981 space shuttle landing, a Carter/Reagan debate, and Jimmy Swaggart's 1988 televised repentance. Images of New York State include photographs of crowds on Jones Beach, farmhouses in the Hamptons, a dance club in Plattekill, New York, and the Culinary Institute of America in Hyde Park. Also included are several images of the Eisenhower Lock on the St. Lawrence Seaway in Massena, New York.
  Subseries I.3 Subjects-New York City contains photographs of buildings, streets and events in Manhattan and the surrounding boroughs. Images date from approximately 1968 to 1987, with many slides undated. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by specific subjects such as "Bridges", "Buildings", "Restaurants & Food" and "Winter Scenes". "Buildings-Hotels" includes several interior images of the New York Palace Hotel. "Education" includes images of public schools, newly desegregated classrooms and classes at New York University, Columbia University and LaGuardia Community College. Images of the 1978 New York Marathon are included in "Competitions-Sports", along with a Jets football game and people gambling at an Off Track Betting branch. Photographs of the proceedings of the Knapp Commission, investigating corruption in the New York City police force, are located with "Events-Miscellaneous". Labor demonstrations include a 1969 teachers strike. Along with Christmas, holiday images include a series taken on Easter, showing women in elaborate hats on Fifth Avenue. "Neighborhoods" includes the East Village, the Lower East Side, Chelsea, Times Square and Washington Heights. Also included are a large number of images from East Harlem in 1976, showing graffiti, empty lots and burned-out buildings. "Occupations" contains several images of dog walkers, police officers and street vendors. "Poverty" is comprised of images of the homeless. "Transportation" includes buses, horse-drawn carriages and images of traffic. Also included are images of transportation stations such as Grand Central Station and John F. Kennedy International Airport. Images of graffiti can be found in "Miscellaneous & Unidentified."
  - Subseries I.1 - Portraits
    - "A" general - Abzug, Bella S. Ackroyd, Dan - 1986 Adams, Eddie - 1985 Agnew, Spiro - 1968 Alda, Alan (2) - 1977, 1979 Allen, Woody - 1978 Akin, susan - 1985 Ali, Muhammad [Alley, Kirstie - See: Steinem, Gloria] Amada, Jorge Anderson, John Anderson, Laurie Anstett, Dorothy - [1968] Appelfeld, Aharon - 1991 Astor, John - 1982 Auth, Tony Avigdor, Arika - 1979 Aucock, Alice - 1984 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - "B" general - Bacharach, Burt Baez, Joan - 1967 Baker, Howard Baldridge, Letitia - 1983 Baldwin, Roger - 1980 Baron, Rose - 1982 Batcha, Robert - 1988 Bathurst, David Beame, Abe Beard, James Ben-Gurion, David - 1969 Bennett, Georgette - 1988 Bertolucci, Bernardo Beuys, Joseph - 1979 Blakey, Art - 1982 Bliss, Anthony A. Bloom, Claire Bloom, Harold Blum, Yehuda Bogdanovitch, Peter - 1973 Borenfreund, Ellen - 1984 Boulez, Pierre Bradley, Bill - 1978 Breslin, Herbert Brightman, Sarah - 1988 Brokaw, Tom - 1982 Buford, Bill [Burton, Richard - See: Taylor, Elizabeth] Bush, Dorothy Walker Bush, George Herbert Walker - 1980 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - "C" general - [Caan, James - See: Pacino, Al] Capote, Truman Capshaw, Kate Carmichael, Hoagy - 1969 Caro, Robert - 1972 [Carter, Amy - See: Letterman, David] Carter, Jimmy & family - 1977 Carter, Rosalynn - 1977 Carey, Hugh [Castelli, Leo - See: Oldenberg, Claes] Castro, Fidel at the United Nations Cheever, John - 1968, 1977 Chojecki, Miroslaw - 1981 Chow, Tina Claiborne, Craig Claiborne, Liz Clark, Ramsey - 1975 Clemente, Francisco at the Palladium nightclub Clinton, Bill - 1986 Colbert, Claudette - 1984 Collingwood, Charles - 1984 Cooke, Terence (Cardinal) at St. Patrick Cathedral, N.Y. - 1987 [Cooper, Alice - See: Dali, Salvador] Cooper, Gordon - 1984 Coppola, Francis Ford Cosby, Bill Cuomo, Mario with wife Matilda Cuomo Currie, Ellen - 1987 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - "D" general - Dali, Salvador - 1972 Davidson, Barry - 1985 Davies, Robertson - 1981 Davis, Kenneth De Armas, Raul - 1985 De Havilland, Olivia - 1985 De Kooning, Willem - 1978 DeLillo, Don - 1988 De Lorean, John Dennehy, Brian - 1988 Dillon, Douglas - 1983 Dinkins, David Disch, Thomas - 1988 Domingo, Placido Donovan Donovan, Hedley - 1978 Dowd, Timothy Duncan, D. Duvall, Robert (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - "E" general - Edelman, Gerald M. Eisenhower, David and julie Eisenman, Peter Elliot, Sarah M. birdwatching in Central Park Ellis, Brett Easton [Evans, Robert - See: McGraw, Ali] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - "F" general - Falwell, Jerry - 1979 Farrow, Mia - 1969 Feltsman, Vladimir - 1987 Ferro, Rober - 1988 Fettner, Anne - 1987 Fierstein, Harvey - 1983 Filipacchi, Daniel - 1988 (See also: Werner, Jan) Flack, Roberta Flutie, Doug Ford, Gerald - 1980 Franzen, Jonathan - 1988 Frazier, Ian - 1986 [Frenay, Craig - See: Claiborne, Craig] Friedan, Betty - 1987 Friedman, Tuvia Fuentes, Carlos - 1988 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - "G" general - Gardiner, Robert - 1984 Garet, Jedd - 1977 [Garr, Terri - See: Letterman, David] Gartner, Gideon Gartner, Michael - 1986 Gautier, Jean Paul Chandi, Rajiv - 1970's Giger, H. R. - 1979 Gilchrist, Ellen - 1984 Ginsberg, Allen - 1978 Ginzburg, Alexander - 1979 Ginzburg, Ralph Gioia, Dana Gish, Lilian Giuliani, Rudolph Giutman, Roy - 1986 Glenn, John Glenn, John Goldernson, Leonard Goldman, William - 1987 Gorey, Edward - 1978 Gotfryd, Bernard Graham, Billy at Madison Square Garden - 1969 Graves, Michael Greene, Doug - 1983 Greene, Gael - 1982 Greenspan, Alan Gregorian, Vartan - 1987 Grigorovich, Yuri Gromyko, Andrei Grooms, Red Grunwald, Henry - 1983 Grutman, Roy - 1986 Guare, John - 1985 Guest, Christopher - 1984 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - "H" general - Haas, Francis - 1988 Hagerty, Julie Haig, Alexander Haimovitz, Matt - 1988 Halberstam, David - 1985 Hamill, Dorothy at Wollman Rink - 1987 [Hana, Timothy - See: Beame, Abe Hanson, Duane - 1978 Hardy, Hugh Haring, Keith - 1985 Harrington, Michael Harris, Jean Harris, Richard Hart, Gary (See also: Mondale, Walter) Hartley, Mariette [Hartman, David - See: Reagan, Nancy] Heaney, Seamus Hejduk, John at Cooper Union - 1969 Hellman, Lillian - 1969 Henson, Jim - 1979 [Herman, Jerry - See: Fierstein, Harvey] Heyman, Alice Hirschfeld, Al - 1988 Hite, Shirley - 1975 Hoffman, Abbie - 1981 Hoffman, Dustin Hoffman, Nicholas V. Holland, James - 1987 Holland, Jimmie [Holzman, Malcolm - See: Hardy, Hugh] Horn, Trevor - 1984 Hottelet, Richard C. Hoving, Walter Hughes, Robert Humphrey, Hubert Hurt, Mississippi John - 1965 Hussein, (King of Jordan) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - "I-J" general - Irwin, Bill Jackson, Henry M. Jackson, Jesse - 1982 Jacob, John E. - 1981 Jardine, Al - 1963 Jarvis, Howard - 1978 Javits, Jacob Jessel, George Jobs, Steve Johnson, Lady Bird Johnson, Lyndon Johnson, Philip - 1984 Jones, Ed "Too Tall" - 1979 Jong, Erica - 1969 Jorgen, Paulo (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
    - "K" general - Kaplan, Helen Singer Karlan, Gil - 1982 Kates, Steve Kaufman, Andy Keach, Stacey - 1969 Kean, Thomas, - 1981 Keene, Christopher - 1984 [Keeshan, Robert (Captain Kangaroo) - See: Cosby, Bill] Keillor, Garrison - 1987 Kelly, Gene with breakdancers Kemp, Jack Kennedy, Ethel [Kennedy, Jacqueline - See: Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy] Kennedy, John, Jr. - 1969 Kennedy, Edward M. (Ted) - 1980-1983 Kert, Larry - 1978 Kertész, André Kirkland, doug Kissinger Henry with Nancy Kissinger - 1982 Klemperer, Werner - 1984 Knaths, Karl - 1968 Koch, Ed - 1982, 1984 Kolvenbach, Peter-Hans Kordiner, Abraham Krasner, Lee - 1983 Kremer, Gidon Krim, Mathilde - 1987 Kumble, Steven Kuralt, Charles (See also: Sawyer, Diane) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
    - "L" general - La Motta, Jake - 1980, 1987 Land, Edwin H. - 1971 Langella, Frank as Dracula Lanyi, Andrew - 1984 Laughlin, James Laurens, Arthur - 1983 (See also: Fierstein, Harvey) Lemming, George - 1988 Lennon, John (See also: Groups - Musical: The Beatles) Letterman, David - 1982,1986 Levi, Primo - 1985 Levine, James Levy, Walter [Lewis, Jerry -- See: Letterman, David] Lewis, Oscar Liberace - 1986 Lichenstein, Charles - 1983 Lichtenstein, Roy - 1969 Lind, J. Lindsay, John - 1969 Loren, Sophia - 1967 Lovelace, Linda with family Lowry, Marsha - 1988 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
    - "M" general - McBain, Ed - 1985 McCarthy, Eugene - 1969 McCartney, Paul (See also: Lennon, John and Groups - Musical: The Beatles) [McEwan, Mark - See: Harley, Mariette] McGraw, Ali [McKean, Michael - See: Guest, Christopher McLaughlin, Ann - 1988 Mahesh Yogi, Maharishi - 1963 Mailer, Norman - 1967 Malamud, Bernard - 1967 Marcasiona, Mary Jane - 1984 Maree, Sydney - 1980 Marx, Groucho Max, Peter Mead, Margaret - 1978 Meier, Richard Meredith, James - 1987 Metzger, Walter - 1983 [Mikas, Jonas - See: Warhol, Andy] Miller, George - 1985 Milosz, Czeslaw - 1985 Mindszenty, Jozsef (Cardinal) - 1965 Minnelli, Liza - 1971 Mintz, David - 1982 Miss, Mary - 1972 Mondale, Joan - 1978 Mondale, Walter Montresor, Beni [Moriarty, Cathy - See: La Motta, Jake] Morris, Anita Morrison, Toni with sons, Harold Morrison and Slade Morrison - 1980, 1987 Moses, Robert - 1978 Mostel, Zero [Mudd, Roger - See: Brokaw, Tom] Mundus, Frank - 1978 Myrdal, Gunnar (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - "N" general - Napier, John - 1982 Newman, Barnett Newman, Paul Nicholas, James Nilsson, Birgit - 1987 Nixon, Richard - 1968 Norman, Jessye - 1982 Nureyev, Rudolf (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - "O" general - Oates, Joyce Carol - 1968, 1971 O'Connor, John Joseph (Cardinal) (See also: Teresa, Mother) O'Faolain, Sean Oldenberg, Claes - 1987 Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy - 1968 Ono, Yoko (See also: Lennon, John) Orlov, Yuri (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - "P-Q" general - Pacino, Al Pang, May - 1983 Pao, Yue-Kong Papp, Joseph - 1982 Pavarotti, Luciano Pei, I. M. - 1980 Pendergrass, Teddy - 1979 Perlman, Itzhak - 1980 (See also: Pei, I. M.) Perry, E. - 1973 [Pfeiffer, Norman - See: Hardy, Hugh] Phelan, John J., Jr. - 1984 Pileggi, Nicholas - 1987 Podhoretz, Norman - 1986 Polini, Mauricio - 1982 Prince, Harold - 1988 Prudhomme, Paul - 1983 (See also: Beard, James) Puzo, Mario - 1967 Quindlen, Anna - 1987 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
    - "R" general - Racz, Andrew - 1984 Radecki, Thomas - 1985 Ragaini, Robert in roof garden - 1982 Rapoport, Nathan - 1984 Rather, Dan - 1984 [Raushcenberg, Robert - See: Mondale, Joan] Ravitz, Diana Reagan, Maureen - 1981 (See also: Carey, Hugh) Reagan, Nancy on set of Good Morning America Reagan, Ronald Regan, Donald - 1988 Reich, Steve Rendell, Ruth Rigg, Diana - 1984 Robinson, Jill Rockefeller, Nelson (See also: Lindsay, John) Rockefeller, Winthrop Rohatyn, Felix - 1985 Rooney, Mickey - 1979 Rosen, Barbara Rosen, Richard - 1988 Rosenblatt, Roger Rosenthal, Benjamin Rossner, Judith Roth, Philip Rush, Norman - 1986 Ryan, Shannon Jo - 1981 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
    - "Sa-Sh" general - Sacks, Oliver W. - 1985 Sadat, Anwar Safer, Morley - 1985 [Saget, Bob - See: Hartley, Mariette] Samaras, lucas - 1982 Samuels, Howard Sapan, Jason - 1982 Savalas, Telly Sawyer, Diane Schapiro, Meyer Schlesinger, Arthur Schmidt, Helmut Schnabel, Julian Schorr, Herbert Schroeder, Pat - 1988 Schwartz, Fred - 1984 Scull, Ethel Sculley, John - 1979 Scully, Vincent - 1979 Segal, George - 1979 Sellers, Peter - 1985 Shamir, Itzhak - 1983 Shannon, Scott Sharf, Kenny - 1985 Sharon, Ariel [Shearer, Harry - See: Guest, Christopher] Sheed, Wilfred - 1987 Sheey, Gail - 1980 Shipp, John Wesley (Offsite-box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Si-Sw" general - Sideroff, Rich Sills, Beverly - 1980, 1984 Silverman, Fred - 1979 Simmons, C. Simmons, Richard D. - 1981 Simon, Neil - 1986 Simon, Paul - 1987 Simon, Sidney Sinatra, Frank - 1980 Singer, Isaac Bashevis Smith, Margaret Chase Smith, Mary-Ann Tirone - 1987 [Smith, Rolland - See: Harley, Mariette] Sondheim, Stephen Sorensen, Theodore Springsteen, Bruce Stapleton, Ruth Carter - 1978 Starn, Doug and Mike - 1987 Steinbrenner, George Steinem, Gloria - 1985, 1988 Stern, Isaac Stevens, Roger - 1985 Stoppard, Tom with Miriam Stoppard Straub, Peter - 1986 Styron, William - 1967 Sullivan, Ed - 1968 (See also: Groups - Musical: The Beatles) Sutzkever, Abraham - 1991 Swift, Graham (Offsite-box 2, Folder 18)
    - "T" general - Tate, Jeffrey Taylor, Elizabeth - 1972 Taylor, James - 1988 Teresa, Mother Thant, U Thatcher, Margaret Thompson, Virgil - 1986 Thorseth, Ragnar - 1984 Timmerman, Jacobo [Tomlin, Lilly - See: Abzug, Bella] Tormé, Mel - 1982 Trillin, Calvin - 1987 Trump, Donald - 1986,1987 (See also: Flutie, Doug; Hamill, Dorothy) Tune, Tommy [Turkel, Ann - See: Harris, Richard] Turner, Ted - 1986 Turoff, Jay Tutu, Desmond - 1986 Twiggy - 1967 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 19)
    - "U-V" general - Uggams, Leslie - 1971 Ustinov, Peter - 1979 Vance, Cyrus - 1976 Van Doren, Mamie - 1975 Vizininczey, Stephen - 1985 Vogel, Herbert and Dorothy - 1985 Volbrecht, Michael - 1985 Vonnegut, Kurt - 1965 [Voznesensky, Andre - See: Ginsberg, Allen] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 20)
    - "W" general - Wagner, Robert - 1960s Waite, Terry - 1985 Warhol, Andy - 1972-1985 Waters, Ethel - 1969 Weil, Simone - 1970s Weizman, Ezer - 1980 Werner, Jan Wertmüller, Lina - 1967 Westlake, Donald - 1988 Williams, Karen Winston, Arnold Winters, Shelley Wolf, Judy in terrace garden Woods, Dana Wyeth, Jamie - 1975 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Y-Z and Groups" Young, Andres (See also: Newman, Paul) Younger, Irving - 1981 [Youngs, Gail - See: Duvall, Robert] Zabar, Eli Zion, Sidney - 1988 Zuckerman, Pinchas Groups - Musical - The Beatles on the Ed Sullivan Show (Offsite-box 2, Folder 22)
  - Subseries I.2 - Subjects
    - Events - American Gathering of Jewish Holocaust Survivors, 1983 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 23)
    - Events - Metrinko Homecoming, 1981 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 24)
    - Events - Press Conferences, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 25)
    - Events - Protests - Resurrection City, Washington, D.C. (Offsite-box 3, Folder 26)
    - Locations - New York State, 1982-1983, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 27)
    - Locations - Louisiana - New Orleans, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 28)
    - Locations - Unidentified, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 29)
    - Military - various, 1983, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 30)
    - Pop Culture - various, 1980-1987, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 31)
    - Science and Medicine - various, 1975-1988, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 32)
    - Shopping - various, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 33)
    - Technology and Industry - various, 1976-1985, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 34)
  - Subseries I.3 - Subjects - New York City
    - Arial Views and Skylines - various, 1970-1986, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 35)
    - Art and Architectural Models - Alice Aycock sculptures Joseph Beuys exhibit Jean Dubuffet sculpture Red Grooms installation Beni Montresor costume designs George Segal sculptures Donald Trump Television City project, 1980-1986, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 36)
    - Bridges - George Washington Bridge Manhattan Bridge Queensboro Bridge Verrazano-Narrows Bridge, 1983-1986, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 37)
    - Bridges - Brooklyn Bridge, 1983. undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 38)
    - Buildings - various, 1979, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 39)
    - Buildings - Churches - St. Patrick's Roman Catholic Cathedral Trinity Church (Offsite-box 3, Folder 40)
    - Buildings - Financial Institutions - Financial Institutions - Various New York Stock Exchange, 1982, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 41)
    - Buildings - Hotels - New York Palace Hotel Plaza Hotel Sherry Netherland Hotel, 1979-1980, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 42)
    - Buildings - Museums, Libraries and Societies - American Museum of Natural History Asia Society The Cloisters Metropolitan Museum of Art National Museum of the American Indian New York Public Library Whitney Museum of American Art, 1979-1986, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 43)
    - Buildings - Office Buildings - American Express Building Citicorp Building Empire State Building IBM Building McGraw-Hill Building Pan Am Building RCA Building Rockefeller Center Seagram Building United Nations Woolworth Building World Trade Center, 1977-1983, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 44)
    - Celebrations - Earth Day, 1970,1980 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 45)
    - Competitions - Various, 1978, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - Competitions - Sports, 1978, 1981, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 47)
    - Demonstrations - Various, circa 1970s, 1981, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 48)